翻译：PwnerHarry（官网演讲稿翻译https://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/22291056）
UP主（主要是根据实际演讲补充演讲稿http://zhuanlan.zhihu.com/p/22391019）
翻译校对：Yi Zhang、UP主
时间轴、压制：UP主
要空降的请到1分01秒处 (=・ω・=)
本演讲是特朗普2016年8月31日在亚利桑那州凤凰城关于移民政策的演讲
试翻了人名地名 可能不准 以英文字幕为准
Oh, what a crowd. What a beautiful crowd.
哦 这么多人 这么多优秀的人
That's a lot of people in Phoenix.X2 Thank you very much. Thank you.
这么多人在凤凰城啊 谢谢大家
Thank you, Phoenix.
感谢凤凰城的小伙伴们
I am so glad to be back in Arizona,
能回到亚利桑那州我特别开心
a state that has a very very special place in my heart.
这是个在我心中有非常特殊地位的州
I love the people of Arizona and together, we are going to win the White House in November.
我爱亚利桑那州的人们 十一月的时候我们一起会赢下白宫
Now, you know, this is where all begin for me, remember the massive crowd also.
这里是我竞选的发家之地 别忘了那天的那一群人
So, I say, let's go and have some fun tonight. We are going to Arizona, OK?
所以我说 我们今晚就一起哈皮吧 我们会拿下亚利桑那州的 没错吧
This will be a little more different. This won't be a rally speech per se.
今晚的演讲会有些不同 我不会搞传统的集会演讲
Instead, I am going to deliver a detailed policy address
今晚 我的演讲内容是详细的政策
on one of the greatest challenges facing our country today: illegal immigration.
关于我们国家目前面对的最大挑战之一 非法移民问题
I have just landed having returned from a very important and special meeting with the President of Mexico
我回来刚着陆前和墨西哥总统来了一次特殊会晤
a man I like and respect very much, and a man who truly loves his country, Mexico.
他是一个我喜欢而且很敬佩的人 一个真心爱自己国家的人
And by the way, just like I am a man who loves my country, the United States.
就像我自己 我是个深爱着美利坚合众国的人
We agreed on the importance of ending the illegal flow of drugs, cash, guns and people across our border,
对于那些在我们边境非法流动的毒品 资金 枪支 移民还有贩毒团伙
and to put the cartels out of business.
我们双方一致同意要消灭他们
We also discussed the great contributions of Mexican-American citizens to our two countries,
我们还讨论了墨西哥裔美国人对于两国双方的突出贡献
my love for the people of Mexico,
我对墨西哥人民的爱
and the leadership and friendship that we have between Mexico and the United States.
以及我们两国间的领导班子和亲密友谊
It was a thoughtful and substantive conversation, and it will prolong for a while.
这是一次深入且有实质意义的对话 其将影响一段时间
And in the end, we will all gonna win. Both countries, we will all gonna win.
最后 我们能达到双赢
This is the first of what I expect will be many many conversations in a Trump Administration
我期待我所领导的政府的首要工作
(we are going to go) about creating a new relationship between our two countries.
就是通过更多会晤来塑造新型美墨双边关系
But it's going to be a fair relationship.
但这得是公平的关系
We want fairness.
我们想要公平
But to fix our immigration system, we must change our leadership in Washington.
然而 想要修理我们的移民体制 我们必须换掉华盛顿的领导班子
And we must change it quickly.
还得换得快点
Sadly, sadly, There is no other way.
悲剧的是除此之外别无他法
The truth is, our immigration system is worse than anybody ever realized.
事实上 我们的移民体制比任何人意识到的状况还要糟糕
But the facts aren’t known because the media won’t report on them,
但是因为媒体不报道 其中的事实并不为人所知
the politicians won’t talk about them,
政客们对此无可奉告
and the special interests spend a lot of money trying to cover them up.
特殊利益团体出了很多钱来让报道出现偏差来掩盖事实
Because they are making an absolute fortune. That's the way it is.
绝对是因为他们在闷声发大财
Today on a very complicated and very difficult subject, you will get the truth.
今天你们将会在这样复杂困难的问题中得到真相
The fundamental problem with the immigration system in our country is that it serves the needs of
我国移民体制的根本问题是 它只为以下几种人服务
wealthy donors, political activists and powerful powerful politicians.
富有的金主 政治活动家和有权势的政客
So you can do...Thank you.
……（被打断） 谢谢资磁
Let me tell you who it does not serve: it does not serve you, the American people. Doesn't serve you.
要我说 他们并不为你们——美国人民服务 并不
When politicians talk about immigration reform, they usually mean the following:
当政客们谈到移民政策的改革
amnesty, open borders, and lower wages.
他们通常指的就是特赦 开放边境和压低工资
Immigration reform should mean something else entirely:
而移民政策的改革的意义应该是完全不同的
it should mean improvements to our laws and policies to make life better for American citizens.
加强我们的法律和政策 让美国公民的生活变得更好
But if we are going to make our immigration system work,
但如果我们想让我们的移民体制正常运作
then we have to be prepared to talk honestly
我们就得做好准备好开诚布公地
and without fear about these important and very sensitive issues.
无所忌讳地讨论这些重要的敏感问题
For instance, we have to listen to the concerns that
举例来说 我们得听取
working people, our forgetten working people,
来自那些被遗忘的劳动人民的忧虑
have over the record pace of immigration
譬如创造新高的移民速度
and its impact on their jobs, wages, housing, schools, tax bills, and general living conditions.
以及它对他们工作 薪水 住房 教育 税务和整体生活条件方面的冲击
These are valid concerns, expressed by decent and patriotic citizens from all backgrounds. All over.
这些都是来自不同背景正直爱国公民的实实在在的关切
We also have to be honest about the fact
我们必须得实事求是
that not everyone who seeks to join our country will be able to successfully assimilate.
并不是每个想要移民我国的人都能融入我国环境
Sometimes it’s just not gonna work out.
有时候就是办不成
It is our right as a sovereign nation to choose immigrants
我们美国作为主权国家有权选择
that we think are the likeliest to thrive and flourish and love us.
那些我们认为最有可能在这里成功并且爱我们的移民
Then there is the issue of security.
接下来是安全问题
Countless innocent American lives have been stolen
之所以无数无辜美国人的生命被夺去
because our politicians have failed in their duty to secure our borders and enforce our laws,
是因为我们的政客没能切实履行守护边境 严格执法的职责
like they have to be enforced.
而这正是应该按照法律去执行
I have met with many of the great parents who lost their children
我已和很多失去了自己孩子的父母见面 他们之所以失去自己的孩子
to Sanctuary Cities and open borders.
就因为国内存在对非法移民的庇护之城 以及开放的边境
So many people. So many many people. So sad.
那么多人都悲剧了啊
They will be joining me on the stage in a later while.
他们晚些时候会和我一起登台演讲
And I look forward to introduce them. These are amazing amazing people.
我很希望把他们介绍给大家 他们都是很优秀的人
Countless Americans who have died in recent years would be alive today
如果不是现政府采取的开放边境的政策
if not for the open border policies of this Administration.
这些年来无数的生命都应该能被挽救
And the administration that causes this horrible horrible thought process
而导致这一切糟糕后果的政府
is called Hillary Clinton.
叫做希拉里
This includes incredible Americans like 21-year-old Sarah Root.
例如21岁的优秀美国人萨拉·鲁特
The man who killed her arrived at the border, entered federal custody,
凶手到达边境 被联邦羁押
and then was released into a U.S. community
他被释放到一个美国社区
under the policies of the White House, Barack Obama and Hillary Clinton.
因白宫（奥巴马和希拉里）的现行政策
Weak, weak, weak policies. Weak and foolish policies.
真是脆弱又愚蠢的政策
He was released again after the crime, and now he’s out there at large.
犯罪后（又）被释放了 现在他还逍遥法外
Sarah had graduated from college with a 4.0,
萨拉以GPA4.0这个的高分从大学毕业
top student in her class, one day before her death.
名列班级第一 而这一切就发生在她死前一天
Also among the victims of the Obama-Clinton open borders policy
奥巴马——克林顿的开放边界政策的牺牲品
was Grant Ronnebeck, a 21 year-old convenience store clerk and a really good guy in Mesa, Arizona.
还有亚利桑那州梅萨市21岁的便利店店员格兰特·伦尼贝克 没错这是个好人
Lot of you have known about Grant.
你们中的很多人都知道他
He was murdered by an illegal immigrant gang member
他被一个成为黑帮成员的非法移民谋杀
previously convicted of burglary, who had also been released from Federal Custody.
这个凶手之前因为偷盗被羁押 又被释放
And they knew it was gonna happen again.
而且他们知道这仍会发生
Another victim is Kate Steinle,
另外一个受害者凯特·斯坦利
gunned down in the Sanctuary City of San Francisco
在难民的收容所旧金山
by an illegal immigrant deported five previous times.
被一个曾被五次驱逐出境的非法移民枪杀
And they knew he was no good.
而他们知道这些移民都不是好人
Then there is the case of 90 year-old Earl Olander,
还有90岁的厄尔·奥兰德
who was brutally beaten and left to bleed to death in his home.
他被残忍地殴打 在家流血至死
90 years old and defenseless.
90岁的长者而且毫无防备
The perpetrators were illegal immigrants with criminal records a mile long,
罪犯有很多前科
who did not meet the Obama Administration’s standards for removal.
却未能达到奥巴马政府所划的“驱逐出境优先级”这个标准
And they knew it was going to happen.
而他们知道这将发生
In California, a 64 year-old Air Force Veteran, a great woman according to everybody that knew her,
在加利福尼亚 退役的64岁的空军老兵 很多人都知道她是个杰出的人
Marilyn Pharis, was sexually assaulted and beaten to death with a hammer.
玛丽莲·法里斯先是被性侵 接着被凶手用一把锤子活生生地砸死
Her killer had been arrested on multiple occasions, but was never ever deported.
杀害她的凶手曾多次被捕 但却从未被驱逐出境
Despite the fact that everybody want him out.
尽管事实上每个人都想让他滚蛋
A 2011 report from the Government Accountability Office found that
2011年 政府审计局的一个报告指出
illegal immigrants and other non-citizens in our prisons and jails together
监狱中的非法移民和其他的非美国公民
had around 25,000 homicide arrests to their names.
犯下的蓄意杀人罪有大约25000起
25,000
25,000起
On top of that, illegal immigration costs our country more than $113 billion dollars a year.
更加重要的是 非法移民使我国每年多支出超过1130亿美元
And this is what we get.
这就是我们的代价
For the money we are going to spend on illegal immigration over the next ten years,
这些未来十年将要花在非法移民上的钱
注：at-risk students:Characteristics of at-risk students include emotional or behavioral problems, truancy, low academic performance, showing a lack of interest for academics, and expressing a disconnection from the school environment.
（摘自维基百科https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/At-risk_students 所以此处翻译为肄业）
we could provide one million at-risk students with a school voucher,
够我们以教育券的方式 来帮助100万肄业的学生
when so many people are wanting.
而这正是很多人期待已久的
While there are many illegal immigrants in our country who are good people, many many,
当然 我们国内的非法移民中也有好人
this doesn’t change the fact that most illegal immigrants are lower-skilled workers with less education
这并不能改变事实——那便是大部分非法移民是低技能水平 低教育水平的人
who compete directly against vulnerable American workers,
但他们直接与（同样低教育低技能）脆弱的美国劳工进行竞争
and that these illegal workers draw much more out from the system than they can ever possibly pay back.
非法移民从体制中获益的部分的远超他们对此的付出
And they are hurting a lot of our people that can not get jobs under any circumstances.
无论如何 他们还会损害我国已有的失业人员
But these facts are never reported.
但是这些事实总是被宣传上有偏差的报道所忽略
Instead, the media and my opponent discuss one thing, and only this one thing:
相反地 媒体和希拉里都这一件事情上跑得很快
the needs of people living here illegally in many cases.
就是这些非法移民的各种诉求
By the way, they were treated better than our vets.
顺便提一下 这些人比我们老兵的待遇还要好
Not gonna happen anymore folks, Nov 8th. Not gonna happen.
11月8号那天给我投票的话这些就不会接着发生了
The truth is, the central issue is not the needs of the 11 million illegal immigrants
事实上 核心问题并不是这1100万非法移民的需求
– or however many there may be.
亦或是别的什么数目
And honestly we’ve been heard that number for years.
实话说这个数字我们已经听了好多年了
It's always 11 million.
老说是1100万
Our government has no idea.
我们政府对此一无所知
It could be 3 million or it could be 30 million. They had no idea what the number is.
也许是300万也许是3000万 他们并不清楚到底有多少非法移民
Frankly, our government has no idea what they are doing on many many fronts, folks.
平心而论 我们的政府在许多领域都图样图森破
But whatever the number, that has never really been the central issue.
管它什么数字 它从来都不是核心问题
It will never be a central issue.
它也不会成为核心问题
It doesn't matter from that standpoint.
从那个立场上来讲这无足轻重
Anyone who tells you that the core issue is the needs of those living here illegally
那些告诉你非法移民的诉求问题是核心问题的人
has simply spent too much time in Washington.
只是在帝都华盛顿呆了太长时间
Only out of touch media elites think the biggest problem facing American society, you know this,
你懂的 只有那些还需要学习一个的媒体精英认为美国社会当今面临的最大问题是
you know this, this is what they talk about,
这就是他们老说的那些
facing American society today is that there are 11 million illegal immigrants who don’t have legal status.
最大问题是1100万非法移民没有合法身份
And they also think the biggest thing, and you know this.
而他们认为最重要的事 你们知道的
It's not nuclear. It's not ISIS. It's not Russia. It's not China. It's Global Warming.
不是核问题 ISIS 俄罗斯 中国 而是气候变暖
To all the politicians, donors and special interests, hear these words from me and all of you today:
下面这些话是我和美国人民送给所有政客 金主 利益集团的——竖起耳朵听好了
there is only one core issue in the immigration debate and that issue is:
移民问题的辩论有且只有一个核心问题
the well-being of the American people.
美国人民的安居乐业
Nothing even comes a close second.
没有啥其他的可谈
Hillary Clinton, for instance, talks constantly about her fears that families will be separated.
举个例子 希拉里常说她担心非法移民的家庭会被拆散
But she’s not talking about the American families
但是她并不提及
who have been permanently separated from their loved ones because of a preventable homicide,
那些被永久拆散的美国家庭 他们现在已经和家人永别 尽管这场凶杀案本可避免
because of a preventable death, because of a murder...
尽管他们可以活下来 尽管凶手……
No, she’s only talking about families who came here in violation of the law.
呵呵 希拉里只会谈论违法进入美国的家庭
We will treat everyone living or residing in our country with great dignity, so important.
我们会对所有合法定居在我们国内的人予以极大的尊重 这非常重要
We will be fair, just and compassionate to all.
我们会对所有人公平 公正并表示同情
But our greatest compassion must be for our American citizens.
但是我们最大的同情得给我们美国公民
President Obama and Hillary Clinton
奥巴马总统和希拉里
have engaged in gross dereliction of duty by surrendering the safety of the American people to open borders.
严重地渎职 放弃了美国人民的安全而开放边境
And you know it better than anybody right here in Arizona, and you know it.
你们亚利桑那州的人们最了解他们<del>（西方的）（大雾）</del>这一套理论
President Obama and Hillary Clinton support Sanctuary Cities,
奥巴马总统和希拉里支持这些非法移民的庇护之城
they support catch-and-release on the border,
他们支持边境的“抓了就放”的政策
they support visa overstays,
他们支持签证过期滞留
they support the release of dangerous dangerous dangerous criminals from detention
他们支持释放处于羁押中的危险（危险！危险！）犯罪分子
– and they support unconstitutional executive amnesty.
——更有甚者 他们<del>（不按照基本法）</del>违反宪法实行行政大赦
Hillary Clinton has pledged amnesty in her first 100 days,
希拉里保证在她上任后的100天内实行大赦
and her plan will provide Obamacare, Social Security and Medicare for illegal immigrants,
她计划会为非法移民提供奥巴马医保 社会保险和医疗保障
– breaking the federal budget.
这将使联邦预算暴涨
On top of that, she promises uncontrolled low-skilled immigration
还有 她保证会带来低技能水平的移民
that continues to reduce jobs and wages for American workers,
持续性地减少美国劳动者的工作和薪水
and especially for African-American and Hispanic workers, within our countries and our citizens.
特别是国内非裔和西裔美籍劳动者
Most incredibly because to me this is unbelievable.
对我而言这实在是难以置信
We have no idea who these people are, where they come from.
我们完全不知道这些人是谁 都从哪儿来
I always say Trojan Horse. What gonna happen, folks?
我常说特洛伊木马 你们说 接下来会发生啥呢
It's not gonna be pretty.
不能让这类事儿发生
This includes her plan to bring in 620,000 new refugees from Syria and that region over a short period of time.
这包含她在短时间内接纳62万新难民的计划
And even yesterday when you were watching the news,
就算你只是昨天看了新闻
you saw thousands of thousands of people coming in from Syria.
也能发现有成千上万的人从叙利亚赶来
What is wrong with our politicians?
我们的政治家出了什么问题
With our leaders if we can call them that.
还有我们的领袖 姑且这么叫他们
What the hell are we doing?
<del>（安姆安格瑞！）</del>我们到底在干啥
Hard to believe. Hard to believe.
不可想象 不可想象
Now that you’ve heard about Hillary Clinton’s plan
现在你们听到了她的计划
– about which she has not answered a single substantive question
她并没有为这个计划进行实质性的答复
– let me tell you about my plan.
下面让我讲讲我的计划
And you know this.
你知道的
All the time from weeks and weeks that making my plan.
当我忙了好几周来制定我的计划
Debating and talking about what about this what about that.
讨论着这个或那个的时候
They never even mention her plan on immigration.
讲到她的移民计划 他们一直对此无可奉告
Because she doesn't want to get into the quagmire.
因为希拉里不想涉足这片烂摊子
It's a tough one.
这很棘手
She has no idea she's doing
她不知道她在干啥
except open borders and let everybody came in,
除了开放边境让所有人进来
and destroy our country by the way.
与此同时摧毁我们的国家
While Hillary Clinton meets only with donors and lobbyists,
当希拉里克里顿只与她的金主和说客会面时
my plan was crafted with the input from federal immigration officers,
我的政策却由联邦移民官员
These are very great people.
这些人都是很厉害的人
along with top immigration experts anywhere in these country who represent workers, not corporations,
以及全国各地顶尖的移民专家——他们代表劳工阶层利益 而非企业界——编撰修订
very important to us.
这对我们很重要
I also worked with lawmakers who’ve led on this issue on behalf of American citizens for many years,
我和这些领域内的为美国公民利益奔波多年的立法专家进行合作
and most importantly, I’ve met with the people directly impacted by these policies, so important.
最重要的是 我已经和受这些政策直接影响的人会过面
Number One: are you ready?
第一条 你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
你准备好了吗
We will build a wall along the Southern Border.
我们会在南方边境造一道长城
And Mexico will pay for the wall.
同时墨西哥会为此背锅
100%
100%的额度
They don't know it yet, but they are gonna to pay for that.
他们对此尚不知情 但是他们会为此付出
And their great people and great leaders are gonna to pay for the wall.
而他们伟大的人民和领导将为这堵墙而付出
On day one, we will begin working on an impenetrable physical tall powerful beautiful sudden border wall.
自我上台的第一天起 我们就会着手设计一个无法穿透的又高又强还漂亮的骤然升起的边境实体墙
We will use the best technology, including above-and below-ground sensors, as the tunnels,
我们会用最好的技术 包括地上和地下的传感器 去检测隧道
remember that, above and below,
记住 是地上和地下的传感器
above and below ground sensors,
地上和地下的传感器
towers, aerial surveillance and manpower to supplement the wall,
瞭望塔 空中支援和人力来支持它
find and dislocate tunnels, and keep out the criminal cartels,
找到并摧毁隧道 让毒贩团伙无处可走
and Mexico, you know that, will work with us I really believe it,
而且 我相信墨西哥会和我们一起解决问题的
Mexico will work with us I absolutely believe it,
我绝对相信墨西哥会和我们合作
and especially after meeting with their wonderful wonderful president today, I really believe.
特别是我今天和他们那个高到不知道哪里去了的总统谈笑风生之后
They want to solve this problem along with us, and I'm sure they will.
他们想和我们一道解决这个问题 同时我相信他们能做到
Number Two: We are going to end Catch-And-Release.
第二条 我们要结束抓了就放的现状
We catch and they are going. We catch them going.
我们抓住他们 然后就跑了 我们发现他们在跑
Under my Administration, anyone who illegally crosses the border will be detained
在我的治理下 任何非法穿越边境的人都会被拘留
until they are removed out of our country.
直到他们被驱逐出国境
and back to the country from which they came.
遣返回他们之前的国家
And they will be brought great distances.
他们会被遣返到很远的距离
We are not dropping them right across. They learn that.
我们不仅仅只是把他们遣返回邻国 他们对此很熟练
President Eisenhower : "They'd drop them across, right across and they'd come back. And across."
艾森豪威尔总统曾说过“他们把他们扔到对面 他们还会回来 并再度重复”
And when they were thrown to a long distance all of a sudden and that was the end.
而在短时间内把他们遣返到很远的地方 这事儿就不会再发生了
We will take them great distances.
我们不仅会把他们遣返到很远的地方
But we will take them to the country where they came from, OK?
还会把他们遣返回原籍
Number Three...Number Three! This is the one I think is so great.
第三条 我认为是特别重要的一条
It's hard to believe people don't even talk about it.
难以置信 很多人甚至不再谈论此事
Zero tolerance for criminal aliens.
对非法移民罪犯零容忍
It's zero! Zero!
绝对一点都不能容忍
Zero!
绝对不能
We don't want they come in here. They don't come in here.
只要我们不想让他们来 他们肯定来不了
According to federal data,
根据联邦数据
there are at least 2 million, 2 million, think of it, criminal aliens now inside our country.
至少有200万非法移民罪犯在我境内
2 million people criminal aliens.
200万非法移民罪犯
We will begin moving them out day one,
我们会从上台后的第一天开始 移除他们
as soon as I take office, day one,
就是我当政的那一天
in joint operations with local, state and federal law enforcement.
和当地 州还有联邦执法机关采取多方位合作
Now, just so you understand, the police, who we all respect.
现在 正如你理解的那样 就是要和受我们尊敬的警察合作
Say hello to them please.
请和他们打个招呼吧
Boy, they don't get the credit they deserve. I can tell you.
我可以告诉你们的是他们并没有获得足够好的待遇
The great people.
都是伟大的人
But the police and the law enforcement, they know who these people are.
同时也就是这些执法者们知道非法移民都是谁
They live with these people. They get marked by these people.
他们常和非法移民打交道 同时成为非法移民的攻击对象
They can't do anything about these people and they want to do it.
但是他们没法进行反击 心有余而力不足
They know who these people are.
这些执法者们知道非法移民都是谁
They want my first hour in office. Those people are gang.
他们想让我执政的第一个小时就为他们服务 而非法移民可都是一帮坏蛋
And you can call them deport it if you want.
想把非法移民驱逐出境 就叫警察
The press doesn't like that term.
媒体并不喜欢这样
You can call them whenever the hell you are. They gone.
管你是谁 都有权叫警察把他们赶走
Beyond the 2 million, there are a vast number of additional criminal illegal immigrants who have fled.
那两百万意外的 还有很多其他的非法移民罪犯 这些人逃过了法律的制裁
But their days have run out.
但他们的好日子很快就要到头了
In this country, the crime will stop.
在这个国家 这类犯罪行为很快就会停止了
They are going to be gone. It will be over.
他们会滚蛋 这场闹剧也将结束
They are going out, and they are going out fast.
他们很快就滚蛋
Moving forward, we will issue detainers for illegal immigrants who are arrested for any crime whatsoever,
我们会处理掉那些因犯罪被羁押起来的非法移民
and they will be placed into immediate removal proceedings,
通过立即驱逐的方式
if we even have to do that.
如果我们非得这么做的话
We will terminate the Obama Administration’s deadly, and it is deadly non-enforcement policies
我们会终结奥巴马政府致命的无执法政策
that allow thousands of criminal aliens to freely roam our streets,
那些政策导致成千上万的非法移民罪犯在我们的街头闲逛
walk around, do whatever they want to do, crime all over the place.
想干啥干啥 然后到处犯罪
That's over. That's over, folks. That's over.
如果这样那就是吃枣药丸 吃枣药丸
Since 2013 alone,
仅在2013年
the Obama Administration has allowed 300,000 criminal aliens to return back into U.S. community
奥巴马政府就让30万非法移民罪犯回到了美国的社区中
注：ICE = Immigration and Customs Enforcement
– these are individuals encountered or identified by ICE
那些是被移民和海关执行署遇到和辨别的
but who were not detained or processed for deportation.
但没被监禁和驱逐的人
Because it won't be politically correct.
因为这<del>（不清真）</del>政治不正确
My plan also includes cooperating closely with local jurisdictions to remove criminal aliens immediately.
我的计划还包括和当地司法部门的合作 赶走那些非法移民罪犯
注：Secure Communities is an American deportation program that relies on partnership among federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies.
（摘自维基百科https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Communities_and_administrative_immigration_policies）
We will restore the highly successful Secure Communities program. Good program.
我们会恢复之前很成功的社区安全计划
注：Section 287(g) authorizes the Federal Government to enter into agreements with state and local law enforcement agencies, permitting designated officers to perform immigration law enforcement functions, pursuant to a memorandum of agreement, provided that the local law enforcement officers receive appropriate training and function under the supervision of sworn U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) officers.
（摘自维基百科https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Immigration_and_Nationality_Act_Section_287(g)）
We will expand and revitalize the popular 287(g) partnerships,
我们会扩大受欢迎的移民法287（g）条款的合作对象并使其重现生机
which will help to identify hundreds of thousands of deportable aliens in local jails.
这能帮我们辨识成百上千关在当地监狱中的可被驱逐的非法移民罪犯
that we don’t even know about.
我们甚至都不知道
Both of these programs have been recklessly gutted by this Administration.
这两个项目都被现政府不顾后果地停止了
And those were programs that worked.
而这两个项目是起作用的
This is yet one more area where we are headed in a totally opposite direction.
这也是我们和现政府有着完全不同主张的又一个领域
There's no common sense. There's no brain power.
他们完全没有常识 没有脑子
None. None. None.
唔识得啊！
On my first day in office, I am also going to ask Congress to pass “Kate’s Law” – named for Kate Steinle
我上任的第一天 还会要求国会通过以凯特·斯坦利命名的凯特法
– to ensure that criminal aliens convicted of illegal reentry receive strong mandatory minimum sentences.
确保再次进入国境的非法移民受到强大的法定审判
Strong!And then we get them out.
强大的 接着我们就把他们赶走
Another reform I am proposing
我提出的另一个改革
is the passage of legislation named for Detective Michael Davis and Deputy Sheriff Danny Oliver,
是以探员迈克尔·戴维斯和副警长丹尼·奥利弗而命名的法规
two law enforcement officers recently killed by a previously-deported illegal immigrant.
这两个执法人员最近被一个已被遣返的非法移民谋杀
The Davis-Oliver bill will enhance cooperation with state and local authorities
戴维斯-奥利弗法案将会加强州政府和当地官方的合作
to ensure that criminal immigrants and terrorists are swiftly identified and removed.
从而确保罪犯移民和恐怖分子被快速识别并消除
And they will go fast. Believe me.
相信我 这些法案很快就会开始实行
We are going to triple the number of ICE deportation officers.
我们将把移民和海关执行署的负责遣返移民的官员数目增加至原来的三倍
Within ICE, I am going to create a new special Deportation Task Force,
在移民和海关执行署中 我会建立一个新的驱逐出境特遣队
focused on identifying
他们会专注于识别
and quickly removing the most dangerous criminal illegal immigrants in America who have evaded justice.
并快速驱逐最危险而且逃过法律制裁的非法移民罪犯
Just like Hillary Clinton has evaded justice, OK.
就和希拉里逃过了法律制裁一样
Maybe they will be able to deport her.
也许他们也能把希拉里遣返
The local police who know every one of these criminals.
当地警方知晓每一个这样的罪犯
And they know each and everyone by name by crime (by) where they live.
通过了解每个人的姓名 犯罪经历和住址
They will work so fast and our local police will be so happy.
移民和海关执行署的官员跑得比谁都快 并让当地的警察非常哈皮
The day don't have to be abused by these thugs anymore.
到了那一天 民警们不再会被这些暴徒侮辱了
There’s no great mystery to it, they’ve put up with it for years.
这背后并没有啥大秘密 毕竟已经身经百战 见得多了
And now, finally, we will turn the tables and law enforcement and our police
现在终于 我们会改变方针
will be allowed to clear up this dangerous and threatening mess.
执法机关将会被允许去清理这个危险且具威胁的烂摊子
We’re also going to hire 5,000 more Border Patrol agents,
我们还会再雇5千个边境巡防职员
Who give me their endorsement. 65,000 give me their endorsement.
就是他们中的6万5千人给我背书
and put more of them on the border, instead of behind desks, which is good.
把他们更多地安排在边界上 而不是办公室里 这是坠吼的
We will expand the number of Border Patrol Stations.
我们会增加边界巡防站的数目
Significantly.
大大地增加
I’ve had a chance to spend time with these incredible law enforcement officers,
我曾有机会和这些了不起的执法官员一起共度时光
and I want to take a moment to thank them.
我想要占用一点时间来感谢他们
What they do is incredible.
他们的所作所为真了不起
Getting their endorsement means so much to me.
我从边境巡逻队警官们那里获得的政治背书对我意味着太多
More to me really than I can say.
多到我无法用语言来表达
Means so much.
真的让人感动
First time they ever endorse a presidential candidate.
因为这是他们第一次给总统候选人背书
Number Four: Block Funding For Sanctuary Cities
第四条 阻断难民庇护城市的资金支持
We block the fundings. No more fundings.
再不给钱了
We will end the Sanctuary Cities that have resulted in so many needless deaths.
我们会停止那些导致了那么多不必要死亡的难民庇护城市
Cities that refuse to cooperate with federal authorities will not receive taxpayer dollars,
不愿和联邦当局合作的城市将不会得到纳税人的钱
and we will work with Congress
我们要和国会合作
to pass legislation to protect those jurisdictions that do assist federal authorities.
通过那些能保障联邦当局立法机关立法权的同时能帮助到他们的法案
Number Five: Cancel Unconstitutional Executive Orders & Enforce All Immigration Laws
第五条 取消违宪的行政命令且执行所有移民法
We will immediately terminate President Obama’s two illegal executive amnesties,
我们会立即终结奥巴马总统的两个非法赦免
in which he defied federal law and the constitution
这两个赦免公然违抗联邦法律和宪法
to give amnesty to approximately 5 million illegal immigrants. 5 million.
给予500万非法移民赦免500万
And how about all of the millions that waiting online,
再看看还有多少个百万移民正等着在线通过呢
going through the process illegally, so unfair.
非法完成移民进度（对于那些合法移民我国的人）太不公平了
Hillary Clinton has pledged to keep both of these illegal amnesty programs
希拉里承诺要保留这些赦免项目
– including the 2014 amnesty which has been blocked by the U.S. Supreme Court.
包括2014年被最高法院否决的赦免
Great.
糟极了
Clinton has also pledged to add a third executive amnesty.
她还保证要再搞一个<del>（大新闻）</del>行政大赦
And by the way, folks, she will be a disaster for our country, a disaster.
大家可别忘了她将会是我们国家的一个灾难
In so many other ways.
包括其他很多领域
And don't forget the Supreme Court of the U.S.. Don't forget that.
别忘了美国的最高法院
When you go to vote on Nov 8th.
在11月8号你投票那天
And don't forget your Second Amendment.
别忘了属于你们的第二修正案
And don't forget the repeal and replacement of Obama Care.
别忘了废除并替换掉奥巴马医保
And don't forget building up our depleting millitary.
别忘了重建我们空虚的军队
And don't forget taking care of our vets.
别忘了关心我们的老兵
Don't forget our vets. They are been forgotten.
我们的老兵已经被遗忘了很久了
Clinton’s plan would trigger a Constitutional Crisis unlike almost anything we have ever seen before.
希拉里的计划会导致空前的宪法危机
In effect, she would be abolishing the lawmaking powers of Congress
实际上 她会废除国会的立法权力
in order to write her own laws from the Oval Office.
以便她在总统办公室里完成钦定并干预美国的法治
And you see what main judgement she has.
你看看她的那场审判
She has seriously bad judgement.
绝对没被好好审判 只是草草了事
Can you imagine?
你敢相信吗
In a Trump Administration, all immigration laws will be enforced.
在我执政时 所有的移民法律会被执行
As with any law enforcement activity, we will set priorities.
就像任何的执法行为 我们会设置优先级
But, unlike this Administration, no one will be immune or exempt from enforcement
但和现政府不同的是 没人能凌驾于法律之上 没人能逃过执法或被豁免
– and ICE and Border Patrol officers will be allowed to do their jobs.
而且移民和海关执行署和边界巡防官员会被允许去履职
The way the jobs are supposed to be done.
就是该干啥干啥
Anyone who has entered the United States illegally is subject to deportation
任何非法进入美国的人都会是驱逐的对象
– that is what it means to have laws and to have a country.
那才是法律和国家的意义
Otherwise we don't have a country.
否则国将不国<del>（共和党则党将不党#滑稽）</del>
Our enforcement priorities will include
我们执法的首要任务
removing criminals, gang members, security threats, visa overstays, public charges
会囊括清除罪犯 黑帮成员 安全威胁 签证过期还呆在国内的人
– that is, those relying on public welfare or straining the safety net,
靠着公共福利过活的或者破坏安全机构的
along with millions of recent illegal arrivals and overstays
以及近期非法来到国内还超长滞留的成百万的非法移民
who’ve come here under this current corrupt Administration.
只是因为腐败的现政府宽容他们 他们才得逞
Number Six: We Are Going To Suspend The Issuance Of Visas To Any Place Where Adequate Screening Cannot Occur
第六条 在不能实行充足移民审查的地方停止提供签证
According to data provided to the Senate Subcommittee on Immigration and the National Interest,
据参议院下属委员会提供的关于移民和国家利益的资料
between 9/11 and the end of 2014,
在9/11和2014年底之间
at least 380 foreign-born individuals were convicted in terror cases inside the United States.
至少380个外国出生的个人参与国内的恐怖事件
And even right now,
甚至就算是现在
the largest number of people are under investigation for exactly this
也有很大一部分人因此受到调查
that we never had in our history of our country.
这是我国历史从未有过之变局
Our country is a mess.
我们国家现在一团糟
We even don't know what to look for anymore, folks.
我们甚至不知道该寻找些什么
Our country has to straighten out now and we have to straighten out fast.
我们国家需要尽快处理掉这个问题
The number is likely higher, but the Administration refuses to provide this information even to Congress.
这个数字可能更大 但是现政府拒绝将这个信息透露给国会
As soon as I enter office,
在我就职后
I am going to ask the Department of State, which has been brutalized by Hillary Clinton, brutalized,
我会马上要求国务院 那个被希拉里糟蹋的国务院
Homeland Security and the Department of Justice
国土安全局 司法部
to begin a comprehensive review of these cases
开展详尽的这些事件的评估
in order to develop a list of regions and countries from which immigration must be suspended
这样可以得到一个区域和国家的列表
until proven and effective vetting mechanisms can be put into place.
除非其中成员的审查机制被证实是有效运转的 否则停止这些移民来源
I call it extreme vetting, right, extreme vetting.
我把这称作极度有效
I want extreme. It's going to be so tough.
审查必须很严格
And if somebody comes in, that's fine.
如果有人想进入我国 没关系
But they gonna be good as extreme.
你必须得有足够好
And if people don't like it, we got our country, folks. Got our country.
如果有人对此表示不满 你有本事说服我们整个国家
Countries from which immigration will be suspended would include places like Syria and Libya.
这个国家列表包括叙利亚和利比亚
And we are going to stop the tens of thousands of people come in from Syria.
也就是说我们要阻止成千上万的叙利亚人入境
We have no idea who they are, where they come from.
我们不知道他们从哪来 都是谁
There's no documentation. There's no paperwork.
没有文件来证明
It's going to end badly folks. It's going to end very very badly.
如果继续放他们进来 美国吃枣药丸
For the price of resettling 1 refugee in the United States,
在美国 安置1名难民的钱
12 could be resettled in a safe zone in their home region, which I agree with 100%.
足以在其祖国安全的区域安置12名 这点我深信不疑
We have to build the safe zones and we will get the money from the gulf states.
我们必须建立（难民所在国的）安全区域 同时我们将从海湾国家中获得资金
We don't want to put up the money. We owe almost 20 trillion dollars.
我们欠了20万亿 没钱再给你们资助了
Double since Obama took office. Our national debt.
奥巴马当政以来国债涨了一倍
But we will get the money from goal six and others.
但是我们可以从第六条还有别的政策中获得资金
We will supervise it and we will build safe zones which is something that I think all of us want to see.
我们也会监督难民所在国并建立安全区域 我想这是我们所有人都愿意看到的
Another reform involves new screening tests for all applicants that include
另一项改革则包含如下议题
, and this is so important especially begin with the right people and we will get the right people,
这是特别重要的尤其是当我们想得到好人的时候
an ideological certification
对所有申请进入我国的人进行思想审查
to make sure that those we are admitting to our country share our values and love our people.
以确保他们接受我们的价值观 并热爱我们的人民
We are very proud of our country, aren't we?
我们对我们的国家很自豪吧
With all its going through, we are very proud of our country.
我们因它过去的历史而自豪
For instance, in the last five years, we’ve admitted nearly 100,000 immigrants from Iraq and Afghanistan
例如 在最近5年 我们从伊拉克和阿富汗引入了将近10万移民
– in these two countries, according to Pew research, a majority of residents say
根据皮尤研究
that the barbaric practice of honor killings against women are often or sometimes justified.
这两个国家中的大多数居民认为荣誉处决女人的暴行常常或有时是公正的
That's what they say.
这就是他们所说的
That's what they say, they justify, right?
这就是他们所说的 他们<del>（要教你的清真）</del>的正义 没错吧
And where admitting up to our country.
而这些就是被接纳入我们国家的人
Applicants will be asked for their views
申请者会被询问他们关于一些问题的看法
about honor killings, about respect for women and gays and minorities,
关于荣誉处决以及尊重女性 同性恋和弱势群体的看法
attitudes on Radical Islam, which our president refuses to say,
还有极端伊斯兰 而这个词正是我们总统拒绝说的
and many other topics as part of the vetting procedure.
以及其他很多方面的看法 作为审查程序的一部分
And if we have the right people doing it, believe me.
我相信我们中有人能完成这个任务
Very very few will slim through the cracks. Hopefully none.
几乎不会有难民通过这道坎的 希望是没有
Number Seven: We will ensure that other countries take their people back when we order them deported
第七条 确保我们驱逐的人会被目标国家接受
There are at least 23 countries
至少23个国家
that refuse to take their people back after they have been ordered to leave the United States,
不愿接受他们被美国驱逐的人们
including large numbers of violent criminals.
包括大量的暴力罪犯
They won't take them back so we say OK we'll keep them.
这些国家不会把接受他们 所以我们就顺理成章地背了这口锅
Not gonna happen with me folks. Not gonna happen with me.
这不会在我这届政府中发生
Due to a Supreme Court decision,
最高法院已经决定了
if these violent offenders cannot be sent home,
如果这些暴徒不能被遣返回家
our law enforcement officers have to release them into your communities.
我们的执法官员就必须把他们放到你们的社区中
And by the way the results are horrific. Horrific.
这结果是极其恐怖的
There are often terrible consequences,
这总会有糟糕的结果
such as Casey Chadwick’s tragic death in Connecticut just last year.
诸如去年康涅狄格州凯茜·查德威克悲剧性的死亡
Yet, despite the existence of a law
尽管存在这么一个法律
that commands the Secretary of State to stop issuing visas to these countries,
能阻止国务卿给这些国家提供签证
Secretary Hillary Clinton ignored this law
前国务卿希拉里无视了它
and refused to use this powerful tool to bring nations into compliance.
拒绝使用这个有利工具让那些国家屈服
And they won't comply if we won't act properly.
如果我们不正确行动 这些国家就不会屈服
Another words, if we had leaders that knew what they were doing,
再说一句话 如果我们有知情的领袖就能阻止他们
which we don't.
然而并没有_(:3」∠)_
The result of her misconduct was the release of thousands of dangerous criminal aliens
由于她严重失职导致了成千上万危险的非法移民罪犯被释放
who should have been sent home to their countries.
而这些非法移民罪犯本应被送回老家
And instead, we have them, all over the place.
但却被我们收留得到处都是_(:3」∠)_
Probably a couple in this room, miserable fact.
也许这里就有一小撮 令人悲哀的事实
But I hope not.
不过我希望没有
According to a report from the Boston Globe,
根据《波士顿环球报》的一个报告
from the year 2008 through 2014, nearly 13,000 criminal aliens were released back into U.S. communities
2008到2014年间 大约13000非法移民罪犯被退回到美国社区
because their home countries would not under any circumstances take them back.
是因为其所属国拒绝接纳
Hard to believe with the power we have.
难以置信我们还有这么强大的军事力量
Hard to believe.
难以置信
We are like the big bully that keeps getting beat up. Did you ever see that?
我们之前可是四处欺负弱小的恶霸 你见过这种情况吗
The big bully that keeps getting beat up.
我们之前可是四处欺负弱小的恶霸
These 13,000 releases have occurred on Hillary Clinton’s watch
这其中都在希拉里就任国务卿期间被释放
– she had the power and the duty to stop it cold and she decided she won’t do it.
她有那个权力和义务去制止 可她没有
And Arizona knows better than most. Exactly what I'm talking about.
而亚利桑那州对此最为了解你们知道我在说什么
Those released include individuals
这些被释放的人
convicted of killings, sexual assault and some of the most heinous crimes imaginable,
犯下包括凶杀 性侵犯和其他能想像到的一些令人发指的罪行
The Boston Globe writes that a globe review of 323 criminals released in New England.
《波士顿环球报》的环球评论指出 在新英格兰有323个罪犯被释放
From 2008 to 2012, found that
自2008年至2012年
as many as 30% committed new offences including rape, attempted murder and child molestation.
这些人中的30%又犯下了包括强奸 谋杀未遂和性侵儿童的新罪行
We take them. We take them.
我们会拿下他们
Number Eight: We will finally complete the biometric entry-exit visa tracking system,
第八条 我们会最终完成基于生物识别的签证进出追踪系统
which we need desperately.
也是我们极其需要的
For years, Congress has required a biometric entry-exit visa tracking system,
国会要求搞一个基于生物识别的签证进出追踪系统已经好多年啦
but it has never been completed.
但是却从来没整成
The politicians are all talking. No action. Never happens. Never happens.
政客们总是高高在上没有行动从未发生
Hillary Clinton, all talkings.
希拉里就是满嘴跑火车
Unfortunately, when they are in action, it's always the wrong decision.
不幸的是当他们在行动时 做出的决定总是错误的
Do you ever notice?
你们注意到了吗
In my Administration, we will ensure that this system is in place
在我领导的政府之下 我们将确保这个系统
and I will tell you it will be on land. It will be on sea. It will be on air.
在陆海空全面上线
We will have a proper tracking system.
我们会有一个有效的追踪系统
Approximately half of new illegal immigrants came on temporary visas and then never ever left.
大约一半的新来的非法移民都靠着临时的签证进来而赖着不走
Why should they?
他们凭什么这么做
Nobody's telling them leave. Stay as long as you are. We will take care of you.
没人劝他们离开想呆多久呆多久我们会解决你们的
Beyond violating our laws,
除了侵犯我们的法律
visa overstays pose a, and they really are a big problem, substantial threat to national security.
过期滞留还会给我们的国家安全造成重大威胁
The 9/11 Commission said that this tracking system should be a high priority
911委员会说这个追踪系统应该优先开发
and “would have assisted law enforcement and intelligence officials in August and September 2001
“在2001年8 9月间本可以帮助执法机关和情报官员
in conducting a search for two of the 9/11 hijackers that were in the U.S. on expired visas.”
搜寻两个在美国过期滞留的911劫机者”
And you know what I want to meant.
你知道这意味着什么
What that could have been?
这怎么能发生啊
Wouldn't that been wonderful, right?
这怎么能发生啊X2
What that could have been?
这怎么能发生啊X3
Last year alone, nearly a half a million individuals overstayed their temporary visas.
单单去年 就有将近50万的过期滞留者
Removing visa overstays will be a top priority of my Administration.
消除过期滞留会成为我的政府中最高优先级
If people around the world believe they can just come on a temporary visa and never ever leave
如果世界上的人们认为用一个暂时的签证来了就能赖着不走
– the Obama-Clinton policy – that's what it is
就像奥巴马和希拉里的政策那样
then we have a completely open border.
那我们就是有一个完全开放的边境了
And we no longer have a country.
国将不国
We must send the message that visa expiration dates will be strongly enforced.
我们必须让世人清楚 签证到期 遣返将会被严格执行
Number Nine: We will turn off the jobs and benefits magnet.
第九条 关闭对非法移民的工作和补助（这个翻译得不好）
注：E-Verify was originally established in 1997 as the Basic Pilot Program to prevent illegal immigrants from obtaining employment illegally in the United States.（摘自维基百科https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/E-Verify）
We will ensure that E-Verify is used to the fullest extent possible under existing law,
我们会确保E-Verify在尽可能广的情况下依法使用
and will work with Congress to strengthen and expand its use across the country.
我们会与国会合作并在国内扩大其适用范围
Immigration law doesn’t exist just for the purpose of keeping criminals out.
移民法并不能仅为了让罪犯远离我国而存在
It exists to protect all aspects of American life
它的存在是为了保护美国人生活的方方面面
– the worksite, the welfare office, the education system and everything else.
工作 福利 教育和很多其他东西
That is why immigration limits are established in the first place.
这就是移民法从一开始就被建立的原因
If we only enforce the laws against crime, then we have an open border to the entire world.
如果我们只是针对犯罪执行法律 我们也是对全球开放边境
I will enforce all of our immigration laws.
我会执行我们的移民法律
The same goes for government benefits.
对于政府利益也一样
The Center for Immigration Studies estimates that
移民研究中心估计
62 percent of households headed by illegal immigrants used some form of cash or non-cash welfare programs,
62%的非法移民的住房使用了种种现金或非现金的福利项目
like food stamps or housing assistance.
例如粮票和住房补贴
Tremendous cause by the way, to our country, tremendous cause.
顺便给我们的财政带来巨大的负担
This directly violates the federal public charge law designed to protect the U.S. treasury.
这样会直接侵犯用于保护美国财政部的联邦公共收费法
Those who abuse our welfare system will be priorities for an immediate removal.
那些滥用我们福利系统的人会被首先遣返
Number 10: We will reform legal immigration to serve the best interests of America and its workers
第十条 重塑合法移民相关政策以确保其能带来给美国及美国劳动者最多的利益
The forgotten people, workers. We are gonna to take care of our workers.
没错 就是那些被遗忘的劳动者们我们会好好对待我们的劳动者的
And by the way, by the way,
与此同时
we are gonna to make great trade deals. We are gonna to renegotiate trade deals.
我们会建立伟大的贸易协议 我们也会对已有的协议进行重新谈判
We are gonna to bring our jobs back home. X2
我们会把工作带回国内X2
We have the most incompatibly work, trade deals.
我们有着极度不完美的贸易协议
Every negotiated probably in the history of the world.
甚至在整个世界的历史上也是如此
注：NAFTA = North American Free Trade Agreement, TPP = Trans-Pacific Partnership
And it starts with NAFTA, and now they go TPP, one of the great disasters.
先是北美自由贸易协定 接着又是跨太平洋伙伴关系协定 后者是重大灾难之一
We are gonna to bring our jobs back home. (3rd)
我们会把工作带回国内X3
And if the companies want to leave Arizona and if they want to leave other states,
如果有公司想要离开亚利桑那州抑或是其他州而去到国外
it gonna be a lot of trouble for them. It's not gonna be easy.
他们一定得尝点苦头
There will be consequence. Remember that.
这是会有后果的
There will be consequence. (2nd)
这是会有后果的X2
They not gonna be leaving,
他们不会离开美国
go to another country, make the product, sell it to the U.S.,
到另外一个国家 制造产品再卖回给美国
and all we end up with these, no taxes and total unemployment.
我们会终结这一切 既不缴税又不增加就业<del>（你是想上天）</del>
It's not gonna be happen. There will be consequences.
这不会发生的这是会有后果的X3
We’ve admitted 59 million immigrants to the United States between 1965 and 2015.
我国在1965到2015年间接受了5900万移民
Many of these arrivals have greatly enriched our country, so true.
其中很多的来客为我国做出了突触的贡献 没错
But we now have an obligation to them, and to their children, to control future immigration
但是我们现在对他们有一个责任 对他们的孩子有一个责任 那就是控制未来的移民
– as we have following, you think, previous immigration waves, we have some big waves,
跟踪过去的移民潮流 你想想看 我们之前的移民也是有巨大的波动的
and tremendously postive things have happened, incredible things have happened,
同时大量积极的东西和难以置信的东西被制造了出来
– to ensure assimilation, we want to ensure that it works,  assimilation, an important word,
确保移民的同化 真正起作用的同化
integration and upward mobility.
整合还有向上流动性
Within just a few years immigration as a share of national population is set to break all historical records.
在仅仅几年间 移民作为国家人口的一部分 已经突破了历史纪录
The time has come for a new immigration commission
是到了一个该建立新的移民委员会
to develop a new set of reforms to our legal immigration system in order to achieve the following goals:
为了达到以下的几个目标而开展一个新的合法移民项目的时候了
To keep immigration levels, measured by population share, within historical norms
保持移民数量等级 根据人口占比测算 限制在历史常态内
To select immigrants based on their likelihood of success in U.S. society,
根据在美国社会中成功立足的可能性
and their ability to be financially self-sufficient.
以及其资金上自足的能力选择移民
We take anybody. Come on anybody. Just come on then.
之前我们接纳任何人
Not anymore.
现在不会了
You know, folks. It's called the two-way stream. It is a two-way stream.
这叫双向流动 你们知道的
We need a system that serves our needs, not the needs of others.
我们需要一个能够满足我们需求的系统 而不是别的什么人的需求
Remember, under a Trump Administrater, it's called America First. Remember that.
记住 在我执政时 美国优先
To choose immigrants based on merit X2, skill and proficiency
根据所获得的成就 技巧和技巧的熟练度来选择移民
Doesn't that sound nice.
听起来不好吗
And to establish new immigration controls to boost wages
建立新的移民控制举措以提高薪资
and to ensure that open jobs are offered to American workers first.
保证公开的工作首先会提供给美国劳动者
And that in particular African-American and Latino workers,
特别是非裔和拉丁裔美国人
who have been shut out in this process so unfairly.
他们一直被排除在这项计划以外 非常不公平
And Hillary Clinton is gonna do nothing.
希拉里则会什么都不干
For the African-American worker, the Latino worker, she's going to do nothing.
尤其是我们的非裔和拉丁裔劳动者
"Give me your vote", she says, "On Nov 8th."
她说 “11月8号那天给我投票吧”
And then she'll say,"So long. See you in 4 years."
然后她会说 “债见 4年后再说吧”
That's what it is. She gonna do nothing.
这就完了 她啥也不会做
And just look at the past. She's done nothing.
就看看过去怎么样过去她就啥也没做
She has been there for 35 years. She's done nothing.(2nd)
吃干饭吃了35年
And I say, what do you have to lose.
要我说 你干嘛一定要选择失败
Choose me. Watch out good way we gonna do together.
选我我们一块闯出一条好路
Watch.
走着瞧
You watch.
你看着
We want people to come into our country,
我们欢迎人们来到我们的国家
but they have to come into our country legally and properly-vetted,
但是必须合法且接受合格的审查
and in a manner that serves the national interest.
必须要符合国家利益才行
We’ve been living under outdated immigration rules from decades ago.
我们很多年来一直在用着老掉牙的移民规则
They are decades and decades old.
真的用了很多年
To avoid this happening in the future,
为了避免未来不会发生这些
I believe we should sunset our visa laws so that Congress is forced
我认为我们应该废止我们的签证法律
to periodically revise and revisit them to bring them up to date.
如此以来 国会应被要求定期重新检查 重新修补它们
They are care their agent.
不过国会更担心他们的员工(:3」∠)_
We wouldn’t put our entire federal budget on autopilot for decades,
几十年了 我们并没有对整个联邦预算不管不问
so why should we do the same for very very complex subject on immigration?
所以我们为啥不讨论移民问题呢 而且移民问题又是这样复杂的主题
Let’s now talk about the big picture.
让我们谈谈大的前景
These ten steps, if rigorously followed and enforced,
以上十点 如果严格遵照执行
will accomplish more in a matter of months
在这个问题上
than our politicians have accomplished on this issue in the last fifty years.
会在几个月间得到我们的政客们过去五十年内未曾得到的成果
Do they happen folks?
这些成果真的会发生吗
Because I am proudly not a politician,
因为我很自豪我不是个政治家
because I am not beholden to any special interest,
因为我并不受啥特殊利益羁绊
I have spent a lot of money in my campaign. I can tell you.
我告诉你我为了竞选 自己花了很多钱进去
I write those checks.
我可是自掏腰包
No body else trump.
没人能胜过我
I will get this done for you and your family and we will do it right.
我会正确地完成这些 为了你们 为了你们的家人
You will be proud of our country again, on your right.
你有权再度对我们国家产生自豪感
We will accomplish all of the steps outlined above,
我们会完成全部以上这些
and when we do, peace and law and justice and prosperity will prevail.
当我们成功时 和平 法律和公正以及繁荣将会胜利
Crime will go down, border crossings will plummet, gangs will disappear
犯罪数量会变少 非法越境数量将会骤降 黑帮会消失
and now the gangs are all over the place.
而现在黑帮到处都是
and welfare use will decrease.
福利的开支会下降
We will have a peace dividend to spend on rebuilding America, beginning with our American inner cities.
我们会通过和平的红利来重建美国 从我们的市中心贫民区开始
So we are gonna to rebuild them, for once and for all.
一次性全部把他们重建
For those here illegally today who are seeking legal status,
对于那些现在是非法来的而想要合法地位的人
they will have one route and one route only:
他们有且只有一条路可走
to return home and apply for re-entry like everybody else
和其他人一样 先回家 遵守规则
under the rules of the new legal immigration system that I have outlined above.
再通过新的合法移民体制进行申请 我在之前提到过
Those who have left to seek entry
那些离开了这里
Those who have left to seek entry under this new system
and it will be an efficient system,
想要在这个新系统下寻求进入我国的人
will not be awarded surplus visas,
并不会被给予多余的签证
but will have to enter under the immigration caps or limits that will be established in the future.
而是必须按照即将发布的移民限制进入
We will break the cycle of amnesty and illegal immigration. We will break the cycle.
我们会打破赦免和非法移民的恶性循环
There will be no amnesty.
绝对不会有赦免的存在
Our message to the world will be this:
我们通告整个世界
you cannot obtain legal status, or become a citizen of the United States, by illegally entering our country.
你无法通过非法入境而得到合法居住状态 或者成为美国公民
This declaration alone will help stop the crisis of illegal crossings and illegal overstays, very importantly.
光是这个宣言就会帮助我们停止非法越境和非法过期滞留而引发的危机
People will know that you can’t just smuggle in, hunker down, and wait to be legalized.
人们将会知道 你不能就这么溜进来 躲猫猫 等着自己合法化
Not gonna work that way.
这种方式不会再起作用
Those days are over.
这种日子即将结束
Importantly.
这非常重要
In several years, when we have accomplished all of our enforcement and deportation goals
很多年内 当我们完成了我们所有的执法任务
– and truly ended illegal immigration for good,
当我们彻底停止了非法移民
including the construction of a great wall, which we will have built in record time
当我们建造完长城 而我们将以创纪录的时间建造长城
and that reasonable cause which you never hear from the government,
当我们不再听到政府编造的合理支出
and the establishment of our new lawful immigration system
当我们确立完新的移民体制
– then and only then will we be in a position to consider the appropriate disposition of those who remain.
也仅在这之后 我们才能到一个能够考虑如何妥善安排那些留下的人
That discussion can take place only in an atmosphere in which illegal immigration is a memory of the past,
那个讨论只能在非法移民已经是过去的光景时才能发生
no longer with us,
不再伴随着我们
allowing us to weigh the different options available based on the new circumstances at the time.
允许我们根据那个时候的新情况权衡不同的可行选项
Right now, however, we are in the middle of a jobs crisis, a border crisis, and a terrorism crisis,
但是现在 我们还在失业危机 边境危机 恐怖主义的危机中
like never before.
而这是从未有过的大变局
All energies of the federal government and the legislative process
联邦政府的全部力量以及立法过程
must now be focused on immigration security.
必须集中到移民安全这个问题上
That is the only conversation we should be having at this time.
这是我们现在唯一应该讨论的问题
Immigration security cut it off.
移民安全这个问题堵住了所有的路
Whether it’s dangerous materials being smuggled across the border,
无论是边境上走私的那些危险物品
terrorists entering on visas, or Americans losing their jobs to foreign workers,
还是靠着签证进到国内的恐怖分子 亦或是美国人的工作被外国人抢走
these are the problems we must now focus on fixing
这些才是我们现在该集中精力去解决的问题
– and the media needs to begin demanding to hear Hillary Clinton’s answer
媒体应该开始要求听听希拉里的答案
on how her policies will affect Americans and their security.
以及听一听她的政策会怎样影响美国人和他们的安全
These are matters of life-and-death for our country and its people,
这些事情关乎我们国家和人民的生死存亡
and we deserve answers from Hillary Clinton.
我们应该从希拉里那里得到答案
And you notice. She doesn't answer.
你会发现 她并没有回答
She didn't go to Louisiana.
她没去路易斯安那
She didn't go to Mexico. She was invited.
她也没去墨西哥 尽管也被邀请了
She doesn't have the strength or the stamina to make America great again.
她既缺乏强壮的身体又缺乏足够的毅力让美国再度伟大
Believe me.
相信我
What we do know, despite the lack of media curiosity,
我们知道的是 尽管少有媒体在这个上面跑得快
is that Hillary Clinton promises a radical amnesty combined with a radical reduction in immigration enforcement.
但是希拉里承诺会带来极端的赦免 顺便再带来对移民执法的极端地减少
Just ask the border patrol about Hillary Clinton. You won't like what you hear.
问一下边境巡逻队关于希拉里的事情 你不会听到好消息的
The result will be millions more illegal immigrants, thousands of more violent crimes,
结果会带来几百万的非法移民 成千上万的新暴力犯罪
and total chaos and lawlessness, that’s what gonna happen.
和全面混乱和无法无天
As sure as you standing there.
几乎和你站在这儿一样确定
This election, and I believe this, is our last chance
相信我 这个大选是最后一次机会
to secure the border, stop illegal immigration, and reform our laws to make your life better.
来保护边境 停止非法移民 改革法律并让你人生更美好
I really believe.
我真的这么认为
This is it. This is our last chance. Nov 8th. X2
就是这样没有下次 11月8号 X2
You got to get out and vote on Nov 8th.
11月8号你们得出来投票
So last chance.
最后一次
So last chance.(2rd)
最后一次X2
And that includes Supreme Court justices and Second Amendment. Remember that.
这还包括最高法院的公正审判和第二修正案 别忘了
So I want to remind everyone what we are fighting for
所以我想提醒每个人 我们在为了什么而奋斗
– and who we are fighting for.
我们在为了谁而奋斗
So I am going to ask these are really special people that I've gonna to know.
所以我想让那些我过去了解过的特殊的人上来讲讲
I'm gonna ask all of the Angel Moms to come join me on the stage right now.
所以我想恳求全部的天使妈妈现在来上台讲话
这一段主要是背书 说的也不难
我就不翻译了 有心者可以自己去搜新闻 另外这并不代表我忽视他们_(:3」∠)_
These are amazing people.
这些人令人称奇
And I am not asking for their endorsement and believe me that.
其实我并没有要求他们给我背书
I just think I got to know so many of them and many more.
我才了解到许多他们的事迹
From our group.
在我们这群人中
But they are incredible people and what they were going through is incredible
但是他们是有着难以置信经历的人
And it's just no reason for itself.
为此而感动不需要别的理由
Let's give them really tremendous end.
有请他们结束演讲
That's tough staff. I want to tell you. That's tough staff.（2nd）
挨过这些真的非常艰难X2
Incredible people.
难以置信的人们
So now is the time for these voices to be heard.
现在是这些声音该被聆听的时刻
Now is the time for the media to begin asking questions on their behalf.
现在是媒体开始质问自己屁股坐哪儿的时刻
Now is the time for all of us, as one country, Democrat and Republican,
现在是我们所有人 作为一个国家 无论是民主党人还是共和党人
liberal and conservative, to band together to deliver justice and safety and security for all Americans.
无论你是自由派还是保守派 团结一致 为所有美国人带来公平 安全和保护的时刻
Let’s fix this horrible horrible problem.
让我们解决这个糟糕的问题
It can be fix quickly.
这可以很快就修复好
Let’s secure our border.
让我们保护我们的边境
Let’s stop the drugs and the crime from pouring into our country.
让我们阻止那些涌向我们国家的毒品和犯罪
Let’s protect our Social Security and Medicare.
让我们保护好我们的社保和医保体系
Let’s get unemployed Americans off of welfare and back to work in their own country.
让我们带着那些失业的美国人远离那种靠着福利而过的日子
This has been an incredible evening.
今天晚上真是极好的
We are gonna remember this evening.
我们每个人都会记住这个晚上
Nov 8th we have to get everybody.
11月8号我们要动员所有人
This is such an important state.
这是这么重要的一个时刻
Nov 8th.
11月8号
We have to get everybody to go out and vote.
我们得让所有人都出来投票
We are gonna bring
我们会让
We are gonna get our country back, folks.
我们能夺回我们的国家
This is a movement. We are gonna to take our country back.
这是一场运动我们能夺回我们的国家
This is an incredible movement.
这确实是一场惊人的运动
The world is talking about it. X2
整个世界都在关注我们X2
And by the way if you have been looking or watching what's happening
顺便说一下如果你过去3 4天
at poll over the last 3 or 4 days, I think you should start looking. X2
都在关注民调的话 现在的好势头也能促使你开始关注民调了
Together, we can save American lives, American jobs, and American futures.
团结一心 我们可以拯救美国人的生命 工作和未来
Together, we can save America itself.
众志成城 我们可以拯救美国
Join me in this mission. We are going to Make America Great Again.
和我一起 参与到让美国再度伟大的使命中
Thank you. I love you. Thank you. God bless you everybody.
感谢各位 上帝保佑你们所有人
谢谢观看 之后是蜜汁ED和退场花絮_(:3」∠)_
第一次制作全程演讲视频 还望多多包涵